For his son, one man will reach for the impossible.
The Pursuit of Happyness is a drama film directed by Gabriele Muccino.
A struggling salesman takes custody of his son as he's poised
to begin a life-changing professional career.
Chris Gardner, played by Will Smith.
Christopher, played by Jaden Smith.
Linda, played by Thandiwe Newton.
Jay Twistle, played by Brian Howe.
Martin Frohm, played by James Karen.
Alan Frakesh, played by Dan Castellaneta.
The Pursuit of Happyness is a 2006 American biographical drama film directed by Gabriele
Muccino and starring Will Smith as Chris Gardner, a homeless salesman.
Smith's son Jaden Smith co-stars, making his film
debut as Gardner's son, Christopher Jr.
The screenplay by Steven Conrad is based on the best-selling 2006 memoir
of the same name written by Gardner with Quincy Troupe.
It is based on Gardner's nearly one-year struggle being homeless.
The intentional misspelling of the film's title comes from a mural that Gardner
sees on the wall outside the daycare facility his son attended.
The movie is set in San Francisco in 1981.
The film was released on December 15, 2006, by Columbia Pictures, and received positive reviews,
with Smith's performance and the emotional weight of the story garnering acclaim.
Smith was nominated for an Academy Award and a Golden Globe for Best Actor.
The film explores themes of work, worker, homeless person,
single parent, san francisco, california.
The tone is uplifting and emotional.